<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.github.loteran.arctis-sound-manager</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>

  <name>Arctis Sound Manager</name>
  <summary>Linux GUI for SteelSeries Arctis headsets</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      Arctis Sound Manager is a Linux application for configuring SteelSeries Arctis
      headsets. It provides a 4-channel audio mixer (Game / Chat / Media / HDMI),
      a full Sonar parametric EQ system, virtual 7.1 surround sound, and device management.
    </p>
    <p>Features:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>4-channel audio mixer with automatic media routing</li>
      <li>Sonar EQ — parametric EQ with 297+ presets, Spatial Audio, Smart Volume</li>
      <li>Micro processing — AI Noise Cancellation, Noise Gate, Compressor</li>
      <li>ANC / Transparent mode control from GUI and headset</li>
      <li>Virtual 7.1 surround via HeSuVi HRTF convolution</li>
      <li>10-band Custom EQ with save/load presets</li>
      <li>Device status — battery, mic mute, sidetone</li>
    </ul>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">ArctisManager.desktop</launchable>
  <icon type="remote" width="128" height="128">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/loteran/Arctis-Sound-Manager/main/docs/images/arctis-manager-icon.png</icon>

  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/loteran/Arctis-Sound-Manager</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/loteran/Arctis-Sound-Manager/issues</url>

  <developer id="com.github.loteran">
    <name>loteran</name>
  </developer>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>Home — 4-channel audio mixer</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/loteran/Arctis-Sound-Manager/main/docs/images/screenshot_home.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Sonar — Parametric EQ with presets</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/loteran/Arctis-Sound-Manager/main/docs/images/screenshot_sonar.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Equalizer — 10-band Custom EQ</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/loteran/Arctis-Sound-Manager/main/docs/images/screenshot_equalizer.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Headset / DAC — Device info</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/loteran/Arctis-Sound-Manager/main/docs/images/screenshot_headset.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />

  <releases>
    <release version="1.1.72" date="2026-06-13">
      <description>
        <p>Line Out controls for Nova Pro Wireless and Nova Elite — the physical 3.5 mm LINE OUT jack on the GameDAC Gen 2 station is now configurable directly from the ASM DAC tab. A new Station Output section appears above the OLED options and is automatically hidden for headsets without a station DAC. The section contains:. Line Out Mode button group: *Speaker* (amplified output for passive speakers) or *Stream* (digital controlled output). Left / Right / Aux volume sliders (0–100 %) — visible only when mode is set to *Stream*, using a single multi-value HID command [0x47, left, right, aux] per adjustment.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.71" date="2026-06-13">
      <description>
        <p>Arctis Nova Pro Wireless X (PID 0x225d) — third hardware variant of the Nova Pro Wireless X, identified in the upstream elegos/Linux-Arctis-Manager project. Uses the same protocol as the existing 0x12e0/0x12e5 variants; all features (EQ, ANC, mic, surround) work identically.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.70" date="2026-06-13">
      <description>
        <p>Device shown as "No device detected" in GUI for always-connected headsets — devices without an online_status block (e.g. Arctis Nova 3 family) produced an empty D-Bus status dict even after the daemon had successfully initialised them, causing the GUI to display "No device detected" indefinitely. A sentinel headset_power_status: online is now injected when _device_ready is True and no status representation is defined. (#80). "Failed to find sink Arctis_Game" error at startup — redirect_audio was called immediately after spawning the pw-loopback processes, before PipeWire had registered the virtual sink. The method now retries up to 5 times (× 0.4 s) before giving up, eliminating the race condition on normal hardware. The final failure is now logged as WARNING instead of ERROR since the sink may legitimately be absent if loopback creation failed upstream. (#80).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.69" date="2026-06-13">
      <description>
        <p>Game and Media channels silent on NixOS module installs — two root causes addressed:. HeSuVi surround graph crashes when plate_1423 (swh-plugins) is absent — on distros without swh-plugins installed, the Distance reverb LADSPA node was generated unconditionally, causing filter-chain to exit immediately. The Distance effect is now silently disabled when plate_1423.so is not found in the standard LADSPA directories, giving working surround without the reverb rather than a crash-loop. (#79).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.68" date="2026-06-12">
      <description>
        <p>asm-setup crashed on NixOS with FileNotFoundError: update-desktop-database — NixOS and other immutable distros don't ship this tool. The call already used check=False but subprocess.Popen raises FileNotFoundError before the return-code check when the binary is absent. The call is now wrapped in try/except FileNotFoundError and silently skipped. (#79). HRIR file from Nix store (3.6 KB stub) passed validation and was never replaced — the Nix store copy has a valid RIFF header in its first 4 bytes but is far too short to be a usable 7.1 impulse response, causing Game and Media channels to be silent. _hrir_valid() now requires the file to exceed 10 KB in addition to having a RIFF header. asm-setup also tries the bundled hrir_assets/ profiles first (no network required) before downloading from GitHub. (#79).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.67" date="2026-06-12">
      <description>
        <p>Microphone monitor source selected instead of real mic — on some setups PipeWire exposes a monitor source before the real capture source, causing ASM to route apps to the monitor loopback instead of the physical microphone. The physical-source lookup now filters out device.class = monitor entries. (#80). Mic audio bypassed Sonar EQ — applications could connect directly to the ALSA source and skip the sonar-micro-eq filter chain. ASM now sets priority.session = 1010 on the Sonar virtual source and explicitly sets it as the default PulseAudio source at startup, so apps land on the EQ pipeline by default. D-Bus status returned {} when device was connected but status bytes unresolved — if the device was ready but device_status was None, the GUI showed "No device detected" even though the headset was online. The D-Bus GetStatus method now synthesises an online sentinel from online_status.online_value in that case.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.66" date="2026-06-12">
      <description>
        <p>HRIR selection silently failed on NixOS (and any read-only source) — apply_hrir_choice used shutil.copy2 which preserves source file permissions and mtime. Since HRIR WAVs live in the Nix store (read-only, epoch timestamp), the copied hrir.wav was also read-only; any subsequent profile selection in Settings → Spatial Audio would fail silently and the convolver would load an invalid file, leaving the Game and Media channels silent while Chat (which bypasses the convolver) still worked. Fixed by unlinking the destination before copying and using shutil.copy (no metadata). (#79). Uninstaller failed on Bazzite / immutable distros when run via curl | bash — the Distrobox delegation path resolved SCRIPT_DIR from BASH_SOURCE[0], which is stdin when piped through curl. The local scripts/distrobox/uninstall.sh was never found and the script exited with an error. Now fetches both _common.sh and distrobox/uninstall.sh to a temporary directory and delegates from there when the local path is unavailable. Added a dedicated NixOS installation section to the README covering both flake and classic (non-flake) paths, with a prominent warning that Settings → Spatial Audio must be opened on first launch to select an HRIR profile — without this step the Game and Media channels are silent.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.65" date="2026-06-10">
      <description>
        <p>OLED splash screen persisted over custom display on devices without a live PipeWire session — the refresh loop slept for the full 5 s REFRESH_INTERVAL even when the 3 s splash had already expired, leaving a ~2 s gap where the device firmware reclaimed the OLED and showed its native UI alongside ASM's splash content. The loop now wakes immediately at splash expiry so the first custom-display frame is pushed without delay. (#76). No interrupt OUT endpoint warning flooded the journal every 2 s — for devices without an interrupt OUT endpoint on their command interface (e.g. Arctis 1 Wireless), ASM correctly falls back to HID SET_REPORT but was logging a WARNING on every status poll. The warning is now emitted once per device attach; subsequent occurrences are downgraded to DEBUG. The flag is reset on teardown so the warning reappears on reconnect. (#74). recreate_loopbacks storm when filter-chain.service crashed repeatedly — if the SteelSeries Sonar filter-chain service crashed and restarted every few seconds (common in Distrobox), each pw-loopback exit triggered a D-Bus RecreateLoopbacks call, causing a rapid stop/start cycle with no net benefit. Calls are now debounced to at most once per 5 s; legitimate Sonar ↔ simple mode switches are unaffected. (#74).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.64" date="2026-06-10">
      <description>
        <p>Multi-theme support — ASM now ships 5 built-in colour themes (SteelSeries, Dark, Light, Ocean, Forest). The active theme is persisted in settings and can be switched live from the device page without restarting the application; every page, dialog and tray menu follows the change immediately. Enhanced bug report diagnostics — PipeWire / container runtime — the automatic bug report now collects the data needed to diagnose audio-routing failures in Distrobox and other container environments: $PIPEWIRE_RUNTIME_DIR, $PULSE_SERVER, container type (Distrobox / Flatpak / Snap / Docker / native), status of pipewire, pipewire-pulse, wireplumber and filter-chain user services, Arctis-filtered PipeWire nodes from pw-dump (with pactl fallback), PipeWire sources, and the last journal entries for pipewire and filter-chain. A missing or empty Arctis-nodes section in a report is now a direct indicator that PipeWire cannot see the device — eliminating the back-and-forth follow-up that issue #74 required.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.63" date="2026-06-09">
      <description>
        <p>Arctis Nova Pro Wired — OLED screen never updated and the daemon spammed OLED USB error: [Errno 110] Operation timed out — the GameDAC Gen 2 firmware validates the HID SET_REPORT wValue strictly, but ASM sent report id 0 in its low byte, so the base station rejected every OLED transfer. The wValue is now built as (report_type &lt;&lt; 8) | report_id (0x0306 for image frames, 0x0206 for brightness/return-to-UI), matching the protocol proven by working third-party tools. (#76). Arctis Nova Pro Wired — headset not detected after boot/login until audio activity (e.g. joining a call) woke the device — a device already plugged in at startup fires no udev add event, so a single failed initial scan was never retried. The daemon now re-scans periodically until the device is fully configured instead of waiting for a hotplug or USB wake event. (#76). Arctis Nova Pro Wired — audio near-inaudible unless volume was cranked to ~95% — control-transfer device commands carried the same incorrect wValue, so the high-gain initialisation never reached the GameDAC. Commands now embed the correct report id in the wValue for devices that require it, opt-in per device so the Nova 7 family and others are unaffected. (#76).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.62" date="2026-06-09">
      <description>
        <p>Font rendering on Bazzite/Linux — all text displayed as blocks — Qt's QSS parser does not support the CSS Level 4 system-ui keyword; it treated it as a literal font name, found nothing, and fell back to a font rendering all glyphs as tofu squares. Replaced with sans-serif, which Qt resolves correctly via fontconfig on all Linux distributions.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.61" date="2026-06-08">
      <description>
        <p>Automatic Sonar preset sync — ASM now downloads new SteelSeries Sonar presets automatically at startup (once per 24 h). A  lists all official presets; the new  fetches it, detects missing presets, and downloads them silently in background to . 3 new Sonar game presets: Forza Horizon 6, Lineage 2, Deep Rock Galactic: Rogue Core. GitHub Action —  auto-regenerates  whenever preset files are pushed to  or .</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.60" date="2026-06-08">
      <description>
        <p>Fedora COPR install failed with a python3-dbus-next file conflict — the RPM bundled the dbus_next module, which collides with Fedora's own python3-dbus-next package (shipped since F40). ASM now bundles dbus-next only on distros whose repos don't provide it, and depends on the system package otherwise: Fedora ≥ 40 use python3-dbus-next, older Fedora still bundle, and the Debian/Ubuntu build auto-detects availability per series. (#73)</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.59" date="2026-06-07">
      <description>
        <p>Arctis Nova Pro Omni: gain and mic sidetone now work — re-analysing the USB capture by opcode showed the Omni uses opcode 0x18 for sidetone (not 0x39, which it ignores) and shifted gain values (low=0x00/high=0x01 instead of 0x01/0x02). The device profile is corrected accordingly. (#70). Arctis Nova Pro Omni: OLED screen support — the OLED driver is now parameterised per device (HID interface, report id, SET_REPORT wValue, dimensions) instead of being hard-coded for the Nova Pro Wireless. The Omni's screen is driven on interface 3 with report id 0x01 / wValue 0x0200, which also stops the OLED Resource busy errors it was logging. The Nova Pro Wireless path is unchanged.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.58" date="2026-06-06">
      <description>
        <p>Arctis Nova Pro Omni controls had no effect — a real Windows USB capture of SteelSeries GG driving the Omni (firmware 1.32.0) revealed its HID control commands lead with report id 0x01, not 0x06 (Nova Pro Wireless) nor 0x07 (previously inferred from third-party OLED drivers). The device profile now leads every command with 0x01 and polls status with 0x01b0; the per-setting opcodes are byte-for-byte identical to the Nova Pro Wireless. Gain, mic, sidetone, EQ, ANC and the other controls should now take effect on the Omni. (#70)</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.57" date="2026-06-06">
      <description>
        <p>OLED weather (and all custom-display content) could vanish after the DAC re-enumerated — the Arctis Nova Pro Wireless re-enumerates on the USB bus at boot, wake and replug. The daemon overwrote its libusb handle without releasing the previous one, so the stale handle kept the interface claimed and every later transfer failed with EBUSY (Resource busy), blanking the custom OLED display and blocking device commands. The handle is now fully released (dispose_resources) before re-claiming on same-device re-enumeration. "Show city" weather toggle on the DAC tab could not be turned off — oled_show_weather_city had no matching configuration entry, so the D-Bus SetSetting call was rejected and the toggle snapped back to on. Added the missing entry. Vertical OLED scroll no longer triggers when the content essentially fits — the layout height was over-counted (separator double-count plus excess weather padding); the natural height now mirrors the real render and a small scroll deadzone was added, so a near-full screen stays still instead of jittering.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.56" date="2026-06-06">
      <description>
        <p>Arctis Nova Pro Omni controls — the Omni (0x2290) now has its own device profile targeting the correct USB layout: control interface 3 (the 64-byte HID endpoint) with HID SET_REPORT transport. In 1.1.55 it reused the Nova Pro Wireless profile (interface 4 with an interrupt-OUT endpoint the Omni does not expose), so the UI appeared but the controls had no effect. DAC command opcodes are still assumed identical to the Nova Pro Wireless, pending confirmation.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.55" date="2026-06-06">
      <description>
        <p>Arctis Nova Pro Omni support — added product ID 0x2290 to the Arctis Nova Pro Wireless device profile. Audio routing (Game/Chat/Media mixer, HeSuVi spatial surround, Sonar EQ) and HID controls are enabled by reusing the Nova Pro Wireless DAC protocol. The status protocol is assumed identical and not yet confirmed by a USB capture, so some reported status values may be inaccurate until verified.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.54" date="2026-06-03">
      <description>
        <p>Arctis GameBuds / GameBuds X support — initial device support for the Arctis GameBuds (PS5/PC, 0x230a) and GameBuds X for Xbox (0x2317) via their 2.4 GHz USB dongle. Supported controls: mic volume, sidetone (Off/Low/Medium/High), noise cancelling mode (Off/Transparency/ANC), ANC/transparency level, volume limiter, wear sense, and auto power-off (up to 90 min). Protocol reverse-engineered from a USB capture; battery level and connection status are not yet available (status protocol unknown).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.53" date="2026-06-02">
      <description>
        <p>Left-click the tray icon to open the window — a single left-click on the Arctis Sound Manager system-tray icon now opens the main window (launching it the first time, raising and focusing it afterwards). Previously the window could only be reached through the tray's right-click context menu. Right-click still shows the context menu.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.52" date="2026-06-02">
      <description>
        <p>Microphone filter-chain crashed PipeWire when ClearCast AI noise cancellation was enabled (#69) — the rnnoise LADSPA plugin (librnnoise_ladspa) aborts when it is fed buffers at a sample rate it was not built for, taking down the whole filter-chain service (pipewire -c filter-chain.conf) and leaving the system with no audio until reboot. The mic filter-chain is now pinned to 48 kHz — the rate rnnoise expects — so the plugin always receives valid buffers. Periodic ~1 s microphone dropouts in apps using echo cancellation (#68) — Discord/Teams/Steam WebRTC echo cancellation drifted against the virtual mic source's clock and reset roughly once per second, silencing the mic for a split second at a steady cadence. Pinning the mic filter-chain to 48 kHz and locking its quantum (node.lock-quantum) removes the resampling and clock drift, so app-side echo cancellation can stay enabled without stuttering.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.51" date="2026-06-02">
      <description>
        <p>Arctis 7+ reported as offline while actually connected — the power-status parser only recognised a single "online" byte (0x02), but the Arctis 7+ firmware reports several online sub-states (0x00, 0x02, 0x03). When the headset was in any of the unmatched states it was treated as powered off, so online detection and audio redirection failed. The parser now enumerates all online states explicitly via int_str_mapping (thanks @Michsior14 — #67). Bumped pygments to 2.20.0 (fixes a low-severity ReDoS advisory in the GUID regex) and pytest to 9.0.3 (dev dependency).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.50" date="2026-06-02">
      <description>
        <p>Arctis Nova 5X (PID 0x2255) support — the 0x2255 variant is now declared in the device YAML, so it is detected and managed like the other Nova 5/5X models. Its udev rule is generated automatically at build time. Unmapped PIDs are surfaced in red in the README device table — any Product ID reported by telemetry but not yet declared in a device YAML is now listed automatically in red, so it can be triaged and promoted into a YAML. The list self-cleans: a PID drops out once it lands in a YAML. The device table also gained an lsusb -d 1038: snippet so users can find their own Product ID.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.49" date="2026-06-01">
      <description>
        <p>RNNoise mic noise-suppression dependency failed to install on Ubuntu (#65) — the plugin is not packaged for Ubuntu or its derivatives (Linux Mint, Pop!_OS, elementary, KDE neon), yet ASM suggested an apt package that has no candidate there. Those distros now build the LADSPA plugin from source in one click (Install / Copy cmd), and the dependency is no longer treated as blocking — the rest of ASM works without it. Debian keeps the apt package; Fedora and Arch are unchanged. The "Copy cmd" button also now preserves command quoting correctly. On the DAC OLED, the EQ-mode badge (S = Sonar, C = Custom EQ) is now shown to the right of the clock instead of on its own line.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.48" date="2026-05-31">
      <description>
        <p>Microphone Background / Impact noise reduction could not be turned off — same Qt.CheckState truthiness bug as the Spatial Audio toggle in 1.1.47; the OFF state is now registered correctly. GUI could crash (SIGABRT) on a quick EQ-mode toggle or when applying a preset from the tray — the background apply thread could be destroyed while still running. Thread cleanup now waits for the thread to fully stop (same class as the Smart Volume slider crash fixed in 1.1.47). The daemon froze for up to several seconds while reloading its configuration (e.g. on ReloadConfigs / loopback recreation) because blocking device discovery ran on the asyncio event loop. That work is now offloaded to a worker thread, keeping the daemon responsive.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.47" date="2026-05-31">
      <description>
        <p>App audio channel assignments were "randomly forgotten" (#64) — moving an app to a channel (e.g. LibreWolf → Media) was only persisted for apps the router was already tracking; an app sitting on the default channel was never recorded, so the manual move was never saved and the app kept reverting. Every observed stream's placement is now recorded, so a later manual move is detected and persisted. Also added LibreWolf, Tor Browser, Waterfox, Floorp, Mullvad Browser, Thorium and ungoogled-chromium to the browsers auto-routed to the Media channel. GUI crash when dragging the Smart Volume → Level slider quickly (#63) — the apply worker (a QThread) could be destroyed while still running during rapid re-applies, aborting the application. Worker cleanup now happens only after the thread has fully stopped. Spatial Audio (and the microphone noise-canceling / noise-gate / compressor) toggles did not save their OFF state (#62) — a PySide6 quirk (bool(Qt.CheckState.Unchecked) is True) meant turning these off was never recorded, so e.g. Spatial Audio OFF was lost when saving a custom preset. The OFF state is now persisted correctly.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.46" date="2026-05-30">
      <description>
        <p>Discord (and other apps) lost their audio sink when changing a Sonar profile — applying a Sonar profile or EQ used to restart the whole PipeWire stack, tearing down every node. Apps that do not re-enumerate their output devices when the PulseAudio server connection drops (Discord/Electron in particular) ended up silent until restarted. Profile and EQ changes now restart only the filter-chain service and recreate the virtual-sink loopbacks dynamically, leaving pipewire/pipewire-pulse untouched, so connected apps keep their sink and audio. Virtual sinks showed a generic "pw-loopback-NNN" name in application output pickers and mixers — the Arctis Game/Chat/Media sinks now expose their proper "Arctis … Game/Chat/Media" name and can be selected as an output device (e.g. as Discord's Chat output). Discord appeared as "WEBRTC VoiceEngine" in a channel's application list — applications that report a generic audio-engine name now fall back to their process binary, so Discord shows as "Discord".</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.45" date="2026-05-29">
      <description>
        <p>Arctis 7X: daemon crashed with "Failed to find command interface endpoint" — some Arctis 7X (and other Arctis 1 family) firmwares expose the vendor HID command interface with an interrupt IN endpoint only, no OUT endpoint. get_command_endpoint_address() raised an exception instead of falling back, crashing the whole daemon before the GUI could appear. ASM now detects the missing OUT endpoint and routes commands over HID SET_REPORT (control transfer) automatically, which is the correct path for such devices (issue #59).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.44" date="2026-05-29">
      <description>
        <p>dinit (Artix): Sonar mode toggle crashed — switching Game/Chat ↔ Sonar called systemctl --user restart … with no dinit branch, raising FileNotFoundError: systemctl on systems without systemd. The toggle now works on dinit (issue #25). dinit (Artix): EQ / Sonar changes had no effect — applying a new equalizer mode ran dinitctl start pipewire-filter-chain, but start is a no-op when the service is already running, so the freshly generated config was never reloaded (systemd correctly used restart). All config-reload paths now use restart on both init systems — this is the root cause of the "EQ does nothing" reports on dinit (issue #25). Centralised init-system handling — introduced service_control.py, a single abstraction over systemctl --user and dinitctl. The logical→real service-name mapping (notably filter-chain → pipewire-filter-chain on dinit) and the start/restart distinction now live in one place instead of being copy-pasted across ~25 call sites in 11 files. Service calls no longer crash when the init manager binary is absent; they log and skip. This removes ~230 lines of duplicated branching and makes the issue #25 class of bugs impossible to reintroduce per-site. Added a regression test suite (tests/test_service_control.py).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.43" date="2026-05-28">
      <description>
        <p>Distrobox container fails to start after reboot on Bazzite / SteamOS / Silverblue — /run/asm-hidraw lives on a tmpfs and is wiped at every boot; the sudo mkdir -p in the install script only ran at container creation time, so on the next boot crun could not stat the bind-mount source and refused to start the container (crun: cannot stat /run/asm-hidraw: No such file or directory). A systemd-tmpfiles drop-in (/etc/tmpfiles.d/asm-hidraw.conf) is now installed on the host, recreating the directory at sysinit.target well before Distrobox starts. Added ConditionPathIsDirectory=/run/asm-hidraw to arctis-manager.service to prevent crash-loops if the directory is somehow absent. Affects all three Distrobox installers (bazzite.sh, steamos.sh, silverblue.sh — issue #59).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>

  <categories>
    <category>Audio</category>
    <category>Utility</category>
  </categories>

  <provides>
    <binary>asm-gui</binary>
  </provides>
</component>
