<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.github.loteran.arctis-sound-manager</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>

  <name>Arctis Sound Manager</name>
  <summary>Linux GUI for SteelSeries Arctis headsets</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      Arctis Sound Manager is a Linux application for configuring SteelSeries Arctis
      headsets. It provides a 4-channel audio mixer (Game / Chat / Media / HDMI),
      a full Sonar parametric EQ system, virtual 7.1 surround sound, and device management.
    </p>
    <p>Features:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>4-channel audio mixer with automatic media routing</li>
      <li>Sonar EQ — parametric EQ with 297+ presets, Spatial Audio, Smart Volume</li>
      <li>Micro processing — AI Noise Cancellation, Noise Gate, Compressor</li>
      <li>ANC / Transparent mode control from GUI and headset</li>
      <li>Virtual 7.1 surround via HeSuVi HRTF convolution</li>
      <li>10-band Custom EQ with save/load presets</li>
      <li>Device status — battery, mic mute, sidetone</li>
    </ul>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">ArctisManager.desktop</launchable>
  <icon type="remote" width="128" height="128">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/loteran/Arctis-Sound-Manager/main/docs/images/arctis-manager-icon.png</icon>

  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/loteran/Arctis-Sound-Manager</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/loteran/Arctis-Sound-Manager/issues</url>

  <developer id="com.github.loteran">
    <name>loteran</name>
  </developer>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>Home — 4-channel audio mixer</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/loteran/Arctis-Sound-Manager/main/docs/images/screenshot_home.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Sonar — Parametric EQ with presets</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/loteran/Arctis-Sound-Manager/main/docs/images/screenshot_sonar.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Equalizer — 10-band Custom EQ</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/loteran/Arctis-Sound-Manager/main/docs/images/screenshot_equalizer.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Headset / DAC — Device info</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/loteran/Arctis-Sound-Manager/main/docs/images/screenshot_headset.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />

  <releases>
    <release version="1.1.61" date="2026-06-08">
      <description>
        <p>Automatic Sonar preset sync — ASM now downloads new SteelSeries Sonar presets automatically at startup (once per 24 h). A  lists all official presets; the new  fetches it, detects missing presets, and downloads them silently in background to . 3 new Sonar game presets: Forza Horizon 6, Lineage 2, Deep Rock Galactic: Rogue Core. GitHub Action —  auto-regenerates  whenever preset files are pushed to  or .</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.60" date="2026-06-08">
      <description>
        <p>Fedora COPR install failed with a python3-dbus-next file conflict — the RPM bundled the dbus_next module, which collides with Fedora's own python3-dbus-next package (shipped since F40). ASM now bundles dbus-next only on distros whose repos don't provide it, and depends on the system package otherwise: Fedora ≥ 40 use python3-dbus-next, older Fedora still bundle, and the Debian/Ubuntu build auto-detects availability per series. (#73)</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.59" date="2026-06-07">
      <description>
        <p>Arctis Nova Pro Omni: gain and mic sidetone now work — re-analysing the USB capture by opcode showed the Omni uses opcode 0x18 for sidetone (not 0x39, which it ignores) and shifted gain values (low=0x00/high=0x01 instead of 0x01/0x02). The device profile is corrected accordingly. (#70). Arctis Nova Pro Omni: OLED screen support — the OLED driver is now parameterised per device (HID interface, report id, SET_REPORT wValue, dimensions) instead of being hard-coded for the Nova Pro Wireless. The Omni's screen is driven on interface 3 with report id 0x01 / wValue 0x0200, which also stops the OLED Resource busy errors it was logging. The Nova Pro Wireless path is unchanged.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.58" date="2026-06-06">
      <description>
        <p>Arctis Nova Pro Omni controls had no effect — a real Windows USB capture of SteelSeries GG driving the Omni (firmware 1.32.0) revealed its HID control commands lead with report id 0x01, not 0x06 (Nova Pro Wireless) nor 0x07 (previously inferred from third-party OLED drivers). The device profile now leads every command with 0x01 and polls status with 0x01b0; the per-setting opcodes are byte-for-byte identical to the Nova Pro Wireless. Gain, mic, sidetone, EQ, ANC and the other controls should now take effect on the Omni. (#70)</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.57" date="2026-06-06">
      <description>
        <p>OLED weather (and all custom-display content) could vanish after the DAC re-enumerated — the Arctis Nova Pro Wireless re-enumerates on the USB bus at boot, wake and replug. The daemon overwrote its libusb handle without releasing the previous one, so the stale handle kept the interface claimed and every later transfer failed with EBUSY (Resource busy), blanking the custom OLED display and blocking device commands. The handle is now fully released (dispose_resources) before re-claiming on same-device re-enumeration. "Show city" weather toggle on the DAC tab could not be turned off — oled_show_weather_city had no matching configuration entry, so the D-Bus SetSetting call was rejected and the toggle snapped back to on. Added the missing entry. Vertical OLED scroll no longer triggers when the content essentially fits — the layout height was over-counted (separator double-count plus excess weather padding); the natural height now mirrors the real render and a small scroll deadzone was added, so a near-full screen stays still instead of jittering.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.56" date="2026-06-06">
      <description>
        <p>Arctis Nova Pro Omni controls — the Omni (0x2290) now has its own device profile targeting the correct USB layout: control interface 3 (the 64-byte HID endpoint) with HID SET_REPORT transport. In 1.1.55 it reused the Nova Pro Wireless profile (interface 4 with an interrupt-OUT endpoint the Omni does not expose), so the UI appeared but the controls had no effect. DAC command opcodes are still assumed identical to the Nova Pro Wireless, pending confirmation.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.55" date="2026-06-06">
      <description>
        <p>Arctis Nova Pro Omni support — added product ID 0x2290 to the Arctis Nova Pro Wireless device profile. Audio routing (Game/Chat/Media mixer, HeSuVi spatial surround, Sonar EQ) and HID controls are enabled by reusing the Nova Pro Wireless DAC protocol. The status protocol is assumed identical and not yet confirmed by a USB capture, so some reported status values may be inaccurate until verified.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.54" date="2026-06-03">
      <description>
        <p>Arctis GameBuds / GameBuds X support — initial device support for the Arctis GameBuds (PS5/PC, 0x230a) and GameBuds X for Xbox (0x2317) via their 2.4 GHz USB dongle. Supported controls: mic volume, sidetone (Off/Low/Medium/High), noise cancelling mode (Off/Transparency/ANC), ANC/transparency level, volume limiter, wear sense, and auto power-off (up to 90 min). Protocol reverse-engineered from a USB capture; battery level and connection status are not yet available (status protocol unknown).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.53" date="2026-06-02">
      <description>
        <p>Left-click the tray icon to open the window — a single left-click on the Arctis Sound Manager system-tray icon now opens the main window (launching it the first time, raising and focusing it afterwards). Previously the window could only be reached through the tray's right-click context menu. Right-click still shows the context menu.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.52" date="2026-06-02">
      <description>
        <p>Microphone filter-chain crashed PipeWire when ClearCast AI noise cancellation was enabled (#69) — the rnnoise LADSPA plugin (librnnoise_ladspa) aborts when it is fed buffers at a sample rate it was not built for, taking down the whole filter-chain service (pipewire -c filter-chain.conf) and leaving the system with no audio until reboot. The mic filter-chain is now pinned to 48 kHz — the rate rnnoise expects — so the plugin always receives valid buffers. Periodic ~1 s microphone dropouts in apps using echo cancellation (#68) — Discord/Teams/Steam WebRTC echo cancellation drifted against the virtual mic source's clock and reset roughly once per second, silencing the mic for a split second at a steady cadence. Pinning the mic filter-chain to 48 kHz and locking its quantum (node.lock-quantum) removes the resampling and clock drift, so app-side echo cancellation can stay enabled without stuttering.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.51" date="2026-06-02">
      <description>
        <p>Arctis 7+ reported as offline while actually connected — the power-status parser only recognised a single "online" byte (0x02), but the Arctis 7+ firmware reports several online sub-states (0x00, 0x02, 0x03). When the headset was in any of the unmatched states it was treated as powered off, so online detection and audio redirection failed. The parser now enumerates all online states explicitly via int_str_mapping (thanks @Michsior14 — #67). Bumped pygments to 2.20.0 (fixes a low-severity ReDoS advisory in the GUID regex) and pytest to 9.0.3 (dev dependency).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.50" date="2026-06-02">
      <description>
        <p>Arctis Nova 5X (PID 0x2255) support — the 0x2255 variant is now declared in the device YAML, so it is detected and managed like the other Nova 5/5X models. Its udev rule is generated automatically at build time. Unmapped PIDs are surfaced in red in the README device table — any Product ID reported by telemetry but not yet declared in a device YAML is now listed automatically in red, so it can be triaged and promoted into a YAML. The list self-cleans: a PID drops out once it lands in a YAML. The device table also gained an lsusb -d 1038: snippet so users can find their own Product ID.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.49" date="2026-06-01">
      <description>
        <p>RNNoise mic noise-suppression dependency failed to install on Ubuntu (#65) — the plugin is not packaged for Ubuntu or its derivatives (Linux Mint, Pop!_OS, elementary, KDE neon), yet ASM suggested an apt package that has no candidate there. Those distros now build the LADSPA plugin from source in one click (Install / Copy cmd), and the dependency is no longer treated as blocking — the rest of ASM works without it. Debian keeps the apt package; Fedora and Arch are unchanged. The "Copy cmd" button also now preserves command quoting correctly. On the DAC OLED, the EQ-mode badge (S = Sonar, C = Custom EQ) is now shown to the right of the clock instead of on its own line.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.48" date="2026-05-31">
      <description>
        <p>Microphone Background / Impact noise reduction could not be turned off — same Qt.CheckState truthiness bug as the Spatial Audio toggle in 1.1.47; the OFF state is now registered correctly. GUI could crash (SIGABRT) on a quick EQ-mode toggle or when applying a preset from the tray — the background apply thread could be destroyed while still running. Thread cleanup now waits for the thread to fully stop (same class as the Smart Volume slider crash fixed in 1.1.47). The daemon froze for up to several seconds while reloading its configuration (e.g. on ReloadConfigs / loopback recreation) because blocking device discovery ran on the asyncio event loop. That work is now offloaded to a worker thread, keeping the daemon responsive.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.47" date="2026-05-31">
      <description>
        <p>App audio channel assignments were "randomly forgotten" (#64) — moving an app to a channel (e.g. LibreWolf → Media) was only persisted for apps the router was already tracking; an app sitting on the default channel was never recorded, so the manual move was never saved and the app kept reverting. Every observed stream's placement is now recorded, so a later manual move is detected and persisted. Also added LibreWolf, Tor Browser, Waterfox, Floorp, Mullvad Browser, Thorium and ungoogled-chromium to the browsers auto-routed to the Media channel. GUI crash when dragging the Smart Volume → Level slider quickly (#63) — the apply worker (a QThread) could be destroyed while still running during rapid re-applies, aborting the application. Worker cleanup now happens only after the thread has fully stopped. Spatial Audio (and the microphone noise-canceling / noise-gate / compressor) toggles did not save their OFF state (#62) — a PySide6 quirk (bool(Qt.CheckState.Unchecked) is True) meant turning these off was never recorded, so e.g. Spatial Audio OFF was lost when saving a custom preset. The OFF state is now persisted correctly.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.46" date="2026-05-30">
      <description>
        <p>Discord (and other apps) lost their audio sink when changing a Sonar profile — applying a Sonar profile or EQ used to restart the whole PipeWire stack, tearing down every node. Apps that do not re-enumerate their output devices when the PulseAudio server connection drops (Discord/Electron in particular) ended up silent until restarted. Profile and EQ changes now restart only the filter-chain service and recreate the virtual-sink loopbacks dynamically, leaving pipewire/pipewire-pulse untouched, so connected apps keep their sink and audio. Virtual sinks showed a generic "pw-loopback-NNN" name in application output pickers and mixers — the Arctis Game/Chat/Media sinks now expose their proper "Arctis … Game/Chat/Media" name and can be selected as an output device (e.g. as Discord's Chat output). Discord appeared as "WEBRTC VoiceEngine" in a channel's application list — applications that report a generic audio-engine name now fall back to their process binary, so Discord shows as "Discord".</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.45" date="2026-05-29">
      <description>
        <p>Arctis 7X: daemon crashed with "Failed to find command interface endpoint" — some Arctis 7X (and other Arctis 1 family) firmwares expose the vendor HID command interface with an interrupt IN endpoint only, no OUT endpoint. get_command_endpoint_address() raised an exception instead of falling back, crashing the whole daemon before the GUI could appear. ASM now detects the missing OUT endpoint and routes commands over HID SET_REPORT (control transfer) automatically, which is the correct path for such devices (issue #59).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.44" date="2026-05-29">
      <description>
        <p>dinit (Artix): Sonar mode toggle crashed — switching Game/Chat ↔ Sonar called systemctl --user restart … with no dinit branch, raising FileNotFoundError: systemctl on systems without systemd. The toggle now works on dinit (issue #25). dinit (Artix): EQ / Sonar changes had no effect — applying a new equalizer mode ran dinitctl start pipewire-filter-chain, but start is a no-op when the service is already running, so the freshly generated config was never reloaded (systemd correctly used restart). All config-reload paths now use restart on both init systems — this is the root cause of the "EQ does nothing" reports on dinit (issue #25). Centralised init-system handling — introduced service_control.py, a single abstraction over systemctl --user and dinitctl. The logical→real service-name mapping (notably filter-chain → pipewire-filter-chain on dinit) and the start/restart distinction now live in one place instead of being copy-pasted across ~25 call sites in 11 files. Service calls no longer crash when the init manager binary is absent; they log and skip. This removes ~230 lines of duplicated branching and makes the issue #25 class of bugs impossible to reintroduce per-site. Added a regression test suite (tests/test_service_control.py).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.43" date="2026-05-28">
      <description>
        <p>Distrobox container fails to start after reboot on Bazzite / SteamOS / Silverblue — /run/asm-hidraw lives on a tmpfs and is wiped at every boot; the sudo mkdir -p in the install script only ran at container creation time, so on the next boot crun could not stat the bind-mount source and refused to start the container (crun: cannot stat /run/asm-hidraw: No such file or directory). A systemd-tmpfiles drop-in (/etc/tmpfiles.d/asm-hidraw.conf) is now installed on the host, recreating the directory at sysinit.target well before Distrobox starts. Added ConditionPathIsDirectory=/run/asm-hidraw to arctis-manager.service to prevent crash-loops if the directory is somehow absent. Affects all three Distrobox installers (bazzite.sh, steamos.sh, silverblue.sh — issue #59).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.34" date="2026-05-18">
      <description>
        <p>Wireless headset disconnect/reconnect loop — when the USB dongle stays plugged in but the RF link drops (headset powered off or out of range), ASM retried USB commands thousands of times per second with no back-off, preventing the dongle firmware from completing RF re-association. Errors with errno 19 (ENODEV) now trigger a 1-second back-off; after ~10 s of consecutive failures ASM voluntarily releases the handle to let the dongle reconnect cleanly. Removed a redundant request_device_status() call that was firing on every loop iteration instead of the intended 2-second cadence (issue #49).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.33" date="2026-05-18">
      <description>
        <p>ClearCast crash on startup when noise cancellation was enabled — _NoiseCancelingCard connected the toggle signal before creating self._slider; PySide6 fires checkStateChanged synchronously during setChecked(), so restoring an enabled state from the previous session triggered _set_enabled before the slider existed, raising AttributeError (issue #51). README: First launch section — clarified that the daemon starts automatically but the GUI must be opened separately (asm-gui or via the app launcher), documented --systray mode and per-DE autostart methods.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.32" date="2026-05-18">
      <description>
        <p>Audio redirect broken for 8 wireless models — is_device_online() compared on_off parser values ('on'/'off') against YAML online_value: online literally; added aliasing so 'on' ↔ 'online' and 'off' ↔ 'offline' are treated as equivalent (discussion #48). Streams stay on dead loopbacks after disconnect — redirect_audio() changed the default sink but did not migrate active streams; now iterates sink_input_list() and moves every stream sitting on an ASM-owned sink, and persists the choice via pw-metadata for PipeWire restart survival (issue #50). babel missing from packaging metadata — added to PKGBUILD depends, RPM Requires, debian/control Depends, system deps checker, and packaging drift check.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.31" date="2026-05-16">
      <description>
        <p>Microphone routed to wrong device on startup — when the Arctis headset is not yet detected when the filter-chain config is written, target.object was left empty and PipeWire would bind the virtual microphone to the first available source (e.g. a DualSense controller mic). check_and_fix_stale_configs() now detects this condition at daemon startup and patches the target in-place, triggering a filter-chain restart.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.30" date="2026-05-15">
      <description>
        <p>Per-channel output device selection — each audio channel card (Game / Chat / Media) now has a dropdown to route that channel to a specific output sink; systray → Output Routing mirrors the same selection (issue #46). Output device routing saved in profiles — optional checkbox in Save Profile dialog captures the current per-channel routing. Language filter — only languages with ≥ 80 % translation coverage appear in the language selector; names are now displayed in their native script via babel (Français, Deutsch, Polski…) instead of 2-letter codes.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.4" date="2026-05-08">
      <description>
        <p>dinit: filter-chain and video-router stuck stopped after asm-setup — when asm-setup rewrites service files on disk, dinit keeps the old in-memory definition (without restart = true) until explicitly reloaded. Added dinitctl reload for stopped services before starting them so dinit always picks up the current file (issue #25). dinit: D-Bus collision on re-login — the guard preventing a second asm-daemon from starting used dinitctl status, which could miss the race window between dinit's boot-sequence auto-start and asm-setup's explicit start. Replaced with pgrep -f asm-daemon against the actual running process. dinit: filter-chain start race after pipewire restart — asm-setup now waits 0.5 s after a successful dinitctl restart pipewire before starting dependants, giving the PipeWire socket time to come up.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.99" date="2026-05-06">
      <description>
        <p>Adaptive multi-DE autostart — Hyprland, Sway, XDG, systemd, dinit — the "Launch at startup" toggle now automatically selects the right method for the detected desktop environment / init system. On Hyprland it writes exec-once = asm-gui --systray into ~/.config/hypr/hyprland.conf (using a comment marker for clean enable/disable). On Sway it writes exec asm-gui --systray into ~/.config/sway/config. On dinit systems the existing dinitctl enable calls are used. On systemd-based DEs (GNOME, KDE, XFCE, …) the arctis-gui.service approach is kept. Any other setup (i3, unknown, non-systemd distros) falls back to an XDG .desktop file in ~/.config/autostart/. Switching DEs cleans up stale entries from the previous method. Fixes the issue reported by users running Hyprland/CachyOS where the toggle had no effect (closes #30).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.98" date="2026-05-05">
      <description>
        <p>Distrobox hot-plug (issue #26) — the headset can now be plugged in *after* the container is created without requiring --reinstall. A new udev rule (90-asm-hidraw-symlink.rules) maintains /run/asm-hidraw/ as a stable directory of symlinks to SteelSeries hidraw nodes; the container mounts this directory with rslave propagation so additions and removals on the host are immediately visible inside. libusb / PyUSB access from container — /dev/bus/usb is now bind-mounted into the container (rslave), giving PyUSB full access to the USB device tree. Previously only /dev/hidraw* was passed, which blocked the libusb backend entirely. Fedora Silverblue/Kinoite variants auto-detected — distrobox-install.sh now correctly routes Bluefin, Aurora, Sericea, Onyx, and Cosmic Atomic to silverblue.sh (Fedora COPR container) instead of incorrectly using the Arch/AUR container.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.97" date="2026-05-05">
      <description>
        <p>Sonar Media tab (issue #29) — new Media EQ tab placed between Game and Chat in the Sonar page. The channel runs through the HeSuVi 7.1 surround pipeline (same routing as Game), giving music and video apps the full spatial-audio treatment. The complete 300+ preset library ([Game] tag — games, music genres, movies, podcasts) is available from day one. Boost Volume and Smart Volume cards are wired up identically to Game and Chat. Arctis_Media → sonar-media-eq — the Media virtual sink now routes through its own dedicated EQ filter-chain node instead of bypassing Sonar entirely. Stream restore after filter-chain restart remaps effect_input.sonar-media-eq ↔ Arctis_Media correctly.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.96" date="2026-05-05">
      <description>
        <p>dinit support (Artix Linux / issue #25) — ASM now works end-to-end on init systems other than systemd. asm-setup detects dinit via /proc/1/comm and writes service files to ~/.config/dinit.d/ instead of calling systemctl. All service management calls in the GUI (Sonar EQ restarts, autostart toggle, systray shutdown) are branched: systemd systems are completely unaffected, dinit systems get the correct dinitctl start/stop/enable calls. _ensure_dinit_boot_target() — on Artix dinit-userservd there is no default user boot service, so dinitctl enable silently failed ("service 'boot' has no waits-for.d directory"). asm-setup now creates a minimal ~/.config/dinit.d/boot + boot.d/ when absent (never overwrites an existing one), matching the upstream dinit getting-started guide. asm-diag-dinit diagnostic script — reports init system, service file presence, running/enabled state (via waits-for.d symlink inspection), filter-chain, virtual sinks, udev rules and D-Bus in a single read-only pass. Useful for triage on any non-systemd distro.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.95" date="2026-05-04">
      <description>
        <p>OLED horizontal marquee for EQ preset name — when the EQ preset name overflows the 128 px display width, the text now scrolls left pixel-by-pixel. It pauses 2 s at the start (readability), scrolls to the end, pauses 2 s, then snaps back. Speed is controlled by the new Scroll Speed (Horizontal) slider (0 = disabled, 1–5 = slow to fast). OLED horizontal marquee for Profile name — same marquee behaviour applied to the active profile name line. DAC tab — Scroll Speed (Horizontal) slider — new oled_eq_scroll_speed setting controls the horizontal marquee speed for both EQ preset and profile name lines. The existing scroll slider is renamed to Scroll Speed (Vertical).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>

  <categories>
    <category>Audio</category>
    <category>Utility</category>
  </categories>

  <provides>
    <binary>asm-gui</binary>
  </provides>
</component>
