<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.github.loteran.arctis-sound-manager</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>

  <name>Arctis Sound Manager</name>
  <summary>Linux GUI for SteelSeries Arctis headsets</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      Arctis Sound Manager is a Linux application for configuring SteelSeries Arctis
      headsets. It provides a 4-channel audio mixer (Game / Chat / Media / HDMI),
      a full Sonar parametric EQ system, virtual 7.1 surround sound, and device management.
    </p>
    <p>Features:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>4-channel audio mixer with automatic media routing</li>
      <li>Sonar EQ — parametric EQ with 297+ presets, Spatial Audio, Smart Volume</li>
      <li>Micro processing — AI Noise Cancellation, Noise Gate, Compressor</li>
      <li>ANC / Transparent mode control from GUI and headset</li>
      <li>Virtual 7.1 surround via HeSuVi HRTF convolution</li>
      <li>10-band Custom EQ with save/load presets</li>
      <li>Device status — battery, mic mute, sidetone</li>
    </ul>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">ArctisManager.desktop</launchable>
  <icon type="remote" width="128" height="128">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/loteran/Arctis-Sound-Manager/main/docs/images/arctis-manager-icon.png</icon>

  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/loteran/Arctis-Sound-Manager</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/loteran/Arctis-Sound-Manager/issues</url>

  <developer id="com.github.loteran">
    <name>loteran</name>
  </developer>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>Home — 4-channel audio mixer</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/loteran/Arctis-Sound-Manager/main/docs/images/screenshot_home.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Sonar — Parametric EQ with presets</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/loteran/Arctis-Sound-Manager/main/docs/images/screenshot_sonar.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Equalizer — 10-band Custom EQ</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/loteran/Arctis-Sound-Manager/main/docs/images/screenshot_equalizer.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Headset / DAC — Device info</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/loteran/Arctis-Sound-Manager/main/docs/images/screenshot_headset.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />

  <releases>
    <release version="1.2.7" date="2026-07-21">
      <description>
        <p>Arctis_Game / Arctis_Chat / Arctis_Media could appear duplicated in the mixer, with one copy stuck silent, after a daemon crash or a forceful systemctl restart. Each virtual channel is a pw-loopback process kept alive across brief hiccups with node.linger=true; when the daemon itself died without going through a clean shutdown, those processes survived it as orphans the next daemon instance had no record of, so it started three brand new ones with the exact same names right alongside the old ones — PipeWire accepts the duplicates without complaint. The daemon now sweeps for and terminates any leftover loopback claiming a channel's name before starting its own, so a restart always comes back to a clean set of three, however the previous instance went down. Apps routed to the "Output" channel could play into silence. The last hop of that channel — its equaliser output into the external sink (HDMI, TV, speakers) — was the only one in ASM that belonged to nobody: it was not covered by the link ownership applied to Game and Media, nor by the watchdog that re-establishes the Chat and surround outputs. Every filter-chain restart tore that link down and nothing ever put it back, so an application pinned to the Output channel kept playing into a dead end, with no sound and no error message. The watchdog now enforces this hop too, following the external output you selected. Releasing the headset no longer leaves USB interfaces in limbo. ASM claims every USB interface it uses when it takes the device over, but on teardown it released only one of them before handing the device back to the kernel driver — which cannot take back an interface still held by another process. Should that happen while switching between two different headset models, the affected interfaces ended up owned by neither ASM nor the kernel until the device was replugged. Claim and release now cover the same set.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.2.6" date="2026-07-21">
      <description>
        <p>New tray "Maintenance" submenu to restart the audio engine or ASM daemon without a terminal. There was previously no discoverable way to recover from a stuck filter-chain or a config that only takes effect after a restart — the daemon isn't a systemd/dinit unit a user would know to look for ("how do I restart the asm daemon? there's no systemctl service", asked on Discord). The tray now offers "Restart audio engine" (filter-chain only — the common case for applying a regenerated config), "Restart ASM" (the daemon and filter-chain, plus the video router if it was running), and "Regenerate audio configs" (force-repairs stale Sonar/HeSuVi filter-chain configs, then restarts filter-chain). All three go exclusively through the existing service_control abstraction (so they work identically on systemd and dinit), run off the UI thread so the tray never freezes, never touch pipewire itself, and report success or failure via a tray notification. The submenu greys out with an explanation if no service manager (systemctl/dinitctl) is present. Virtual surround could still oversaturate after upgrading to 1.2.5. That release added a fast-lookahead limiter to the HeSuVi chain to fix clipping on hot HRIRs, but the fix only applied to *newly generated* configs — anyone who already had a sink-virtual-surround-7.1-hesuvi.conf from an earlier version kept their old, limiter-less config forever, since none of the daemon's staleness checks recognised it as out of date. Generated filter-chain configs now carry a version marker, and the daemon regenerates the surround config whenever its marker is missing or behind the current version — so an update that changes what that config contains actually reaches existing installs, starting with this limiter. Your Immersion and Distance settings are preserved across the repair, and your equaliser configs are left untouched. (reported on Discord by @craciu25_YT).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.2.5" date="2026-07-20">
      <description>
        <p>Virtual surround could clip ("oversaturate") on loud passages with hot HRIRs (e.g. Nahimic 3). The Immersion slider applies a broadband boost (up to +12 dB, +6 dB at the default 50%) to all eight channels *before* the HRTF convolution, and each stereo output is the sum of four convolved channels — with no headroom stage, loud content pushed peaks past 0 dBFS and clipped. A fast-lookahead limiter (LADSPA fast_lookahead_limiter_1913, from swh-plugins — the same package already used for the Distance reverb) is now inserted on the surround output; it tames only the peaks that would clip and leaves quieter content untouched, so hot profiles stop oversaturating regardless of the Immersion setting. The plugin is staged into ~/.ladspa like the reverb so it also loads on the host under Distrobox, and if swh-plugins is unavailable the chain falls back to the previous behaviour with no limiter. (reported on Discord by @craciu25_YT)</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.2.4" date="2026-07-19">
      <description>
        <p>Spatial Audio stayed silent inside Distrobox even after the 1.2.3 fix. On atomic hosts (Bazzite, etc.) where ASM runs in a container, the HeSuVi surround filter includes a LADSPA reverb plugin (plate_1423, from swh-plugins, powering the Distance effect). ASM's daemon scans the container — which has the plugin — but the PipeWire filter-chain that loads the config runs on the *host*, which does not, so the plugin was written by bare name and failed to load there. Because a single failing node takes the whole filter-chain module down, the surround node never appeared and Game/Media were routed at a sink that did not exist — silent. ASM now stages the plugin into ~/.ladspa (shared between container and host) and references it by absolute path so the host can always load it; existing configs are regenerated to pick this up. The same fix covers the Smart Volume and noise-gate plugins, which hit the identical container/host split. (#100, reported by @ninjapinja2)</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.2.3" date="2026-07-18">
      <description>
        <p>Audio no longer defaults to the headset when it comes online. Older versions forced the Arctis Game channel as the default output on startup; that behaviour later moved into the daemon but ended up gated behind a "Redirect audio on connect" option that defaulted to off, so on a fresh setup nothing claimed the default sink and audio stayed on the TV/HDMI. In a Steam Game Mode session this meant every app had to be moved onto the Game channel by hand. The headset is now selected as the default output automatically as soon as it is powered on — and only while it is on, so it never routes you to a dead sink. Turn "Redirect audio on connect" off if you prefer a non-headset default; that choice now sticks. (#135, reported by @zany130). Spatial Audio no longer goes silent when no HRIR profile was chosen. The HeSuVi surround filter reads its impulse response from a WAV that was only written once you explicitly picked an HRIR profile. With none chosen the file was missing, the surround node failed to load, and enabling Spatial Audio routed Game/Media at a node that did not exist — dead silence until the app was closed. A sensible HRIR profile now ships as the default and is put in place automatically, so Spatial Audio works out of the box; you can still switch to any other profile live. As a safety net, if the surround node ever cannot load, Game/Media fall back to the headset's normal output instead of going silent. (#100, reported by @ninjapinja2).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.2.2" date="2026-07-17">
      <description>
        <p>Bluetooth speakers and headphones can now be selected as an output device. The output pickers — per-channel routing on the home page, the tray "Output routing" menu, the Sonar output override, and the external-output setting — only listed ALSA sinks, so Bluetooth devices (bluez_output.*) never appeared. They are now listed everywhere and identified by their stable node name, so they stay selectable even on setups where the device exposes no node.nick. (#134, requested by @akio4800). Game / Chat / Media volume jumped back to 100% on its own. The virtual channel sinks are pw-loopback processes; every time ASM recreated one — after a PipeWire socket change, an EQ-mode switch, a config regeneration, or the watchdog reviving a crashed process — the fresh sink came up at the PipeWire default of 100%, silently discarding the level you had set. Channel volumes are now persisted and re-asserted by the daemon after each recreation (retried until the sink reappears), so a level you set stays put instead of drifting back to full. (#134, reported by @akio4800).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.2.1" date="2026-07-14">
      <description>
        <p>No sound at all after the headset was switched off and back on. Powering the headset off destroys its physical PipeWire sink; powering it back on recreates it as a new node. ASM's filter-chain nodes run with node.autoconnect = false — by design, WirePlumber never links them, ASM owns those links — but nothing was watching the *last* hop, from the EQ/surround chain to the physical output. So that link was never restored, the headset sink stayed suspended, and audio was gone until both filter-chain and arctis-manager were restarted by hand. The loopback watchdog now enforces the final links (Chat EQ and HeSuVi surround → physical output) on every tick, so sound comes back on its own when the headset returns. Installing from the AUR failed with bsdtar: Failed to set default locale and a ModuleNotFoundError on asm-setup. Two independent packaging bugs. The HRIR asset files for the Spatial Sound Card "Shanghai" presets carried a non-ASCII character in their filename, which bsdtar silently skips when the build environment has no UTF-8 locale; they are now named in plain ASCII (ssc_hu), and a settings migration keeps working for anyone who had selected one. Separately, the PKGBUILD installed dbus-next and pulsectl from PyPI during package() — into a site-packages whose Python version depended on whichever interpreter uv happened to pick — and used uv run to execute build scripts, which could create a venv on a different Python than the system one. Both are gone: those two libraries are now declared as proper package dependencies, and the build scripts run on the system Python. (#132, reported by @eapzzz). Streams were shuffled between headset channels when the headset was off. Follow-up to the routing change in 1.2.0: when the headset powers off, streams parked on its virtual sinks are moved to the default output — but if the default output *is* one of the headset's own channels, there is nowhere useful to go, and moving them just undid the user's own channel assignments. ASM now leaves them alone in that case.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.2.0" date="2026-07-14">
      <description>
        <p>Headset reported as offline while it was powered on. ASM detached the kernel driver (usbhid) from the DAC's HID interface but never claimed the interface. An unclaimed interface stays free, so the kernel was liable to rebind usbhid behind our back, after which every USB transfer failed with EIO (errno 5) — the daemon then looped on USB error: [Errno 5] forever with no recovery, leaving the device status frozen on its initial values (headset shown as offline with 0% battery, even though audio kept working). ASM now claims each interface after detaching it, and recovers from EIO by re-acquiring the interface, falling back to a full device reset if that fails. Battery icon stayed visible on a powered-off headset (Nova Pro Wireless, Nova Elite, Nova Pro Omni, Arctis Pro Wireless). The power-off detection added in 1.1.95 only matched the off power status used by the Nova 7/9/1/5 families, while these devices report offline. Power status handling is now centralised in a shared helper that understands both vocabularies. (follow-up to #124). Apps could not be pinned to the Chat or Game channel when the default sink was not the Arctis. The router force-moved any stream sitting on an Arctis virtual sink back to the default sink, and did so before loading the saved routing overrides — so an explicit user choice (e.g. Discord pinned to Chat while the TV is the default output) was silently ignored and undone every couple of seconds. Arctis_Media was missing from that list, which is why only the Media channel appeared to work. Saved overrides are now always honoured, whatever the default sink; streams are only pulled back to the default sink when the headset is actually powered off, and such a move is transient — it never overwrites the user's choice, so the app returns to its channel when the headset comes back.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.100" date="2026-07-13">
      <description>
        <p>Choose which microphone feeds the Sonar Micro EQ. A new "Sonar Micro EQ input" setting lets you keep the default (your Arctis microphone), pick a specific input device, or select "Manual" so ASM stops enforcing the mic routing and leaves whatever you wired up in a patchbay like qpwgraph in place. (#131). Tray icon color setting. The system-tray icon can now follow your system's light/dark theme automatically, or be forced to white or black, for better contrast on panels where it was hard to see. (#130). Spatial Audio OFF is no longer silent on some headsets. On outputs whose ports are exposed without channel names (the Nova Pro Wireless pro-audio output uses AUX0/AUX1 instead of FL/FR), turning Spatial Audio off left the channel with no audio because ASM matched ports by name and found none. It now falls back to positional matching (front-left → first port, front-right → second), so sound keeps flowing with Spatial Audio off. (#129).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.99" date="2026-07-12">
      <description>
        <p>Share and import color themes, just like presets. Any theme you create in the theme editor can now be shared with other ASM users: copy a self-contained share link, save it to a file, or publish it to the community theme gallery. Themes can be imported from a shared link, a file, or by browsing the community — either from the theme editor or from the Import/Export buttons on the Settings page.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.98" date="2026-07-12">
      <description>
        <p>Audio now stays on your speakers/TV after waking from sleep when the headset is off. With the headset powered off — so sound is meant to play through your TV or external speakers — resuming from sleep could bounce media apps (VLC, Spotify, browsers…) back onto the headset's Media output, and the only fix was to toggle the headset off and on. On resume ASM now re-asserts the correct routing based on whether the headset is actually powered on, so audio stays where it belongs. (#128)</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.97" date="2026-07-11">
      <description>
        <p>The Sonar Micro EQ no longer steals your microphone. Adjusting any Sonar Micro EQ setting used to detach the EQ from your headset mic and re-attach it to a different input device (a second microphone), forcing you to fix the routing by hand after every change. ASM now takes the mic capture out of WirePlumber's routing and owns and continuously re-asserts the headset-mic → Micro EQ link, so it can no longer be stolen — while leaving any other app that uses your mic untouched. (#127)</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.96" date="2026-07-11">
      <description>
        <p>The runtime dependency self-healing checker now knows about pw-loopback (which implements the virtual Game/Chat/Media sinks), so a missing one is detected and can be offered for install per distro. (#123)</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.95" date="2026-07-11">
      <description>
        <p>Changing the EQ or toggling Spatial Audio no longer restarts the audio engine. Adjusting EQ gains, the macro sliders or the boost — and switching Spatial Audio on or off — is now applied live to the running filter-chain instead of restarting it. On PipeWire 1.6.7 that restart could crash the filter-chain and briefly cut Game/Media audio or leave Spatial Audio silent; these changes now take effect instantly with no dropout. Changes that genuinely alter the graph (adding/removing an EQ band, switching preset, changing the HeSuVi immersion/distance) still restart as before. (#100, #88). Fixed a rare daemon crash-loop that produced random SIGSEGVs. The daemon spawned its helper processes (pw-dump, pw-loopback, pw-metadata, systemctl…) with a fork() that, while the daemon was talking to the headset over USB in another thread, could corrupt memory and crash it with nonsensical errors (seen as a 10-crash restart loop). Every helper spawn now uses a fork-free posix_spawn path. (#123). The tray battery percentage now disappears when the headset is powered off. The wireless adapter keeps reporting a battery level even when the headset is off, so the tray number used to stay on screen; it now hides once the headset powers down. (#124).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.94" date="2026-07-10">
      <description>
        <p>"Bring audio to headset" button. One click moves any application that ended up on the wrong output device (HDMI, S/PDIF, another sound card) back to your headset — handy when an app is silently playing to a device you're not wearing. Available on the Home page and in the system tray. Audio now follows your "redirect on disconnect" device when you quit ASM, not only when the headset powers off. Closing ASM could previously leave sound on whatever output PipeWire happened to pick; it now switches to your configured device instantly. Phantom "Multiple ASM installations detected". On usr-merge distros (modern Arch/Fedora/Ubuntu) /bin is a symlink to /usr/bin, so a single asm-daemon was counted twice and the app wrongly hid the "Update now" button and warned about a duplicate install. Distinct real paths are now counted, so a normal single install is no longer flagged. (#114).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.92" date="2026-07-09">
      <description>
        <p>Battery percentage in the system tray. The headset battery level is shown as its own full-size item next to the ASM tray icon. Can be turned off with the new Battery % in system tray toggle in Settings → General. (#119). 24-hour / 12-hour clock toggle for the OLED. A new option under the Time element in the DAC tab switches the on-screen clock between 24-hour (14:05) and 12-hour (2:05 PM). "Re-enable EQ" button for safe mode. When the audio filter-chain crash-loop safety net has disabled the EQ, a banner on the Sonar page now lets you re-enable it in one click (previously there was no in-app way out). See the new Troubleshooting section in the README. (#88).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.91" date="2026-07-08">
      <description>
        <p>Passthrough toggle on the Output tab. You can now send audio to the external output device exactly as-is, bypassing the Output EQ profile. When enabled, the EQ curve and macro sliders are greyed out since they no longer affect anything. (#111). Two Electron apps that both report as "Chromium" (e.g. Vesktop and Pear Desktop) would not keep their channels across restarts. The GUI saved the manual routing override under the app's display name instead of the same name+binary key the router reads, so the choice never persisted deterministically. The GUI now stores overrides under the exact key the router uses. (#108). Virtual-channel loopbacks could be stolen by another output device. When a second USB DAC (or any competing sink) was present, WirePlumber kept re-routing the Game/Chat/Media loopbacks to it while the watchdog fought back — an unwinnable, hardware-specific tug-of-war. The loopbacks are now taken out of WirePlumber's routing entirely (node.autoconnect=false) and ASM owns their link to the Sonar EQ directly, so no other device can ever steal them regardless of what is plugged in. (#100).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.90" date="2026-07-07">
      <description>
        <p>Arctis Nova Elite is now recognised when the PC is on the GameHub's rear USB ports 2/3 — in that wiring the base station enumerates with product id 0x2246 instead of 0x2244, which ASM did not know about. (#110). The external output device list refreshes when you open the settings panel — a device plugged in after ASM started now appears without restarting the app, instead of being stuck with the list captured at launch. (#106). Rhythmic crackle / growing xruns on Arctis Nova Pro Wireless. The headset's USB playback endpoint is synchronous (no clock feedback), so the loopback clock drifts against the free-running USB clock and the default ALSA headroom is too small to absorb it. ASM now raises api.alsa.headroom on this device automatically (via a WirePlumber drop-in it only rewrites when it changes), eliminating the crackle out of the box. (#105).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.89" date="2026-07-03">
      <description>
        <p>ASM could crash when the "update available" dialog was closed quickly — the "Copy command" button scheduled a 2-second timer to reset its label, and if the dialog was dismissed before it fired the timer touched an already-deleted Qt button, raising libshiboken: Internal C++ object already deleted. Every such timer is now bound to its widget's lifetime and cancelled when the dialog closes. (#100). Endless loopback relink/recreate loop on WirePlumber 0.5.x (Nova Elite, Distrobox / Steam Deck). WirePlumber's restore-stream could re-pin a virtual-channel loopback (Game / Chat / Media) to the physical headset output on every recreate; the watchdog then fought it in a tight loop, restarting the filter-chain over and over. The loopbacks now opt out of target restoration (state.restore-target=false), and the bug report surfaces any stored Arctis targets so a stale one can be spotted and cleared. (#100). LADSPA plugin detection now works on read-only-rootfs distros (SteamOS / Steam Deck). ASM now searches LADSPA_PATH and ~/.ladspa — the only place a user can add plugins when /usr is immutable — alongside the system directories, so it no longer reports a plugin as missing when the filter-chain can actually load it. The blocking dependency check also verifies the Smart Volume (sc4m_1916) and mic noise-gate (gate_1410) plugins, not just the reverb one, since all three ship in the same package and a single missing .so can crash the whole filter-chain. (#88).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.88" date="2026-07-02">
      <description>
        <p>Apps did not stay in their assigned channel on WirePlumber 0.5.x (Nova Pro Wireless) — the Game and Chat pw-loopback playback nodes only set node.target, whose string-name fallback in WirePlumber 0.5.x is unreliable and sometimes linked the loopback to the physical ALSA output instead of the Sonar EQ node. They now set target.object (the reliable object lookup honoured first by WirePlumber ≥ 0.5) while keeping node.target for 0.4.x compatibility. (#102). The routing override daemon did not restart after being killed — arctis-video-router.service used Restart=on-failure, which systemd never triggers when a process is terminated by SIGTERM (treated as a clean exit), so the router stayed dead and channel assignments were no longer enforced. The router units now use Restart=always. (#102). WirePlumber-induced sink flips were saved as manual overrides — when a stream bounced between the virtual channels, video_router recorded each move as a user choice and overwrote routing_overrides.json with the last random target. A debounce now ignores moves that repeat too rapidly (WirePlumber-induced) so the user's actual channel choice is preserved. (#102).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.87" date="2026-06-30">
      <description>
        <p>Sonar devices (e.g. Arctis Nova Elite) went silent when Spatial Audio was enabled — with surround on, the loopback watchdog mistook a single-cycle transient (the Sonar EQ → HeSuVi surround chain rebuilding) for a mis-routed loopback and killed/recreated the pw-loopback, which churned the graph and fed a self-sustaining loop that muted the channel (and spammed the OLED with Resource busy). The watchdog now waits for the mismatch to persist before acting, and corrects a genuine mislink with a non-destructive pw-metadata relink instead of tearing the loopback down. (#100)</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.86" date="2026-06-28">
      <description>
        <p>"Redirect Audio on Disconnect" did nothing even with a device selected (especially USB outputs) — the settings dropdown only saved your choice when the selected *index changed*, so picking the device that was already displayed (or re-selecting it) saved nothing, and the daemon kept reading an empty value. On top of that, when the stored value didn't match any current device the dropdown silently showed the first device as if it were selected, so the option *looked* configured while nothing was actually persisted. Dropdowns now persist on every pick (including re-selecting the current item) and show an unset state instead of faking a selection (#97). Fedora: the ClearCast / rnnoise noise-suppression plugin couldn't be installed — the install instructions (system-deps dialog, RPM %post, README) pointed at the uriesk/noise-suppression-for-voice COPR + package noise-suppression-for-voice, but that COPR only ships a source package, so dnf install failed with "matches only source packages". Switched to the lkiesow/noise-suppression-for-voice COPR and the ladspa-realtime-noise-suppression-plugin binary package (verified on Fedora 44).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.85" date="2026-06-28">
      <description>
        <p>Arctis Nova Elite "Sage &amp; Gold" colorway (PID 0x2270) is now recognised out of the box (#101). Arctis Nova Elite crashed the daemon at startup — the command interface was declared as interface 0 instead of the real interface 3, so the daemon could not find it and exited on launch. It now targets the correct interface, and the daemon falls back to HID SET_REPORT (control transfer) instead of crashing whenever a unit's command interface is missing (#100). Microphone volume (and other device settings) could reset to the minimum on launch — when a saved setting value was missing while initialising the headset, ASM pushed 0 to the device, dropping the mic to 1/10 instead of your saved level. Missing values now fall back to the device profile's default.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.84" date="2026-06-26">
      <description>
        <p>Wrong version reported in the GUI footer and bug reports — on installs that share a single site-packages directory (typical on Arch/CachyOS, and inside Distrobox), the version lookup matched the *first* enumerated distribution rather than the one that actually ships ASM, so the footer and Report a bug output showed nonsense versions like 0.1 or 1.9.0 for a 1.1.83 install. The version is now resolved by checking which distribution genuinely owns the running arctis_sound_manager package files, while still preferring the copy that is actually imported (resolves a stale ~/.local shadow of the system install). Hardened virtual-sink routing against PipeWire socket changes (Steam Game Mode / Distrobox) — pw-loopback processes are now spawned with the resolved host PipeWire socket pinned in their environment (falling back to /run/user/&lt;uid&gt;/pipewire-0), and the loopback watchdog detects when the active PipeWire socket changes (e.g. a Desktop ↔ Game Mode session switch under Gamescope) and recreates all loopbacks so they rebind to the new socket instead of going silent on the stale one. (#90).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.83" date="2026-06-25">
      <description>
        <p>Package uninstallable on Ubuntu 24.04 (and any Debian/Ubuntu) from the PPA — arctis-sound-manager declared a hard Depends: noise-suppression-for-voice, but that package (the rnnoise LADSPA plugin) is not in the Debian or Ubuntu archives nor the PPA, so apt refused to install ASM at all (Depends: noise-suppression-for-voice but it is not installable). It is now a Recommends:, matching the binary .deb build, so ASM installs cleanly; the optional ClearCast mic suppression plugin is still offered and built from source on demand by ASM's dependency installer. (#96). Dependency installer wrongly tried apt install noise-suppression-for-voice on Debian — the package does not exist on Debian either, so the install would have failed. Debian now builds the LADSPA plugin from source, like Ubuntu and its derivatives. (#96).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.82" date="2026-06-24">
      <description>
        <p>Audio cuts in and out in Steam Game Mode / Gamescope (Bazzite, SteamOS) — under Gamescope, WirePlumber keeps reshuffling routing, so the loopback watchdog saw a permanent mislink and recreated the Arctis_Game / Arctis_Chat / Arctis_Media loopbacks every few seconds, each recreation causing a brief cut, looping forever. The watchdog now has an anti-flapping guard: when a channel is recreated 3 times within 30 s it enters a cooldown (60 s, doubling up to 5 min) during which it is left alone — a stable loopback, even if temporarily mislinked, is far less disruptive than constant cuts. (#90). Filter-chain crash-loop left audio permanently broken (Steam Deck / SteamOS) — when the PipeWire filter-chain SIGSEGVs on startup (e.g. a LADSPA plugin present in a Distrobox container but missing on the host), systemd restarted it endlessly, so the virtual sinks kept appearing and disappearing. ASM now detects the crash-loop, moves its EQ configs aside ("safe mode") and restarts once more to give flat-but-stable audio instead of perpetual cuts. (#88). Phantom "update available" that never goes away (Fedora and similar) — a leftover pip install --user copy in ~/.local shadowed the distro package on sys.path, so ASM read that stale copy's old version and nagged about an update that was already installed. ASM now reports the version of the package actually running, detects a shadowing pip install and shows a clear "multiple installations detected" message instead, and the dnf update command uses --refresh so a real new version is never hidden by stale COPR metadata.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.81" date="2026-06-20">
      <description>
        <p>YouTube and browser audio silent when ASM is running — sonar-output-eq was generated with media.class = Audio/Sink/Internal even in bypass mode, making it invisible to normal apps. WirePlumber had memorised Firefox → effect_input.sonar-output-eq in its stream-properties database, then refused to connect any new stream to that node (Internal nodes cannot be targeted by PulseAudio-compat clients), leaving Firefox suspended with no sink. The node is now Audio/Sink with priority.session = 1 so apps can connect to it while it is never auto-selected as the default output. Same fix applied to the active 8-channel path. Audio routing broken after daemon restart without the system tray — the arctis-manager systemd unit now declares Wants=filter-chain.service and After=filter-chain.service. Previously, restarting the daemon alone left the filter-chain stopped, causing all Sonar EQ loopbacks (sonar-game-eq, sonar-chat-eq, sonar-media-eq) to become orphaned and be recreated every 15 s until WirePlumber degraded. System tray forced Arctis_Game as default sink unconditionally on startup — the GUI start() method called pactl set-default-sink Arctis_Game regardless of headset state. When the headset was off, Firefox and any other app opening after ASM started were routed to a dead sink. Default-sink redirection is now owned exclusively by the daemon (redirect_audio_on_connect / on_disconnect logic).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.80" date="2026-06-20">
      <description>
        <p>3 new Sonar EQ presets from SteelSeries GG 113.0.0 — *007 First Light*, *Subnautica 2* and *Virtua Fighter 5 R.E.V.O World Stage* are now bundled for the Game channel. Output (HDMI) channel silent after profile switch or device change — the sonar-output-eq filter-chain config hardcoded audio.channels = 8 and a stale node.target pointing to a non-existent hdmi-surround71 device. ASM now queries PipeWire at config-write time to detect the active HDMI/DisplayPort sink and adapts channel count and position automatically (2.0 stereo, 5.1 surround, 7.1 surround). HDMI sinks are preferred over S/PDIF in auto-detection. Flat EQ for presets in SteelSeries GG 113+ format — GG 113.0.0 changed the preset export format, wrapping all settings under a data key. Affected bundled presets (*Forza Horizon 6*, *Deep Rock Galactic: Rogue Core*, *Lineage 2*) were silently rendered as flat/bypass. The parser now handles both formats.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.79" date="2026-06-19">
      <description>
        <p>pacman mirror 404 auto-retry in deps dialog — when installing a missing dependency via the system deps dialog on Arch/CachyOS, a desynchronized mirror (HTTP 404 on the package file) caused the install to fail silently. The dialog now captures pacman output, detects the mirror-sync error pattern, and automatically retries with pacman -Syy to force a database refresh before running the original install command. A guard flag prevents infinite retry loops.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.78" date="2026-06-19">
      <description>
        <p>3 new Sonar EQ presets from SteelSeries GG 113.0.0 — *Pure*, *Precision* and *Immersion* from the official SteelSeries GG 113.0.0 preset list are now bundled for the Game, Chat and Media channels. Per-channel EQ apply no longer interrupts the sibling channel — applying a preset or sliders on the Game channel used to restart both the Game and Media loopbacks (and vice-versa), causing a ~1.5 s audio cut on the channel that was not touched. The apply-worker now calls the new RecreateLoopbackSingle D-Bus method to restart only the loopback for the channel that was actually edited. Chat remains unaffected as before. (issue #85 — thanks @cookiekiller!). **weather_* settings no longer spam [ERROR] Unknown general setting configuration** — weather_enabled, weather_location, weather_lat, weather_lon, weather_units and weather_city_display are stored in GeneralSettings but had no matching ConfigSetting entry, so every SetSetting D-Bus call hit the unknown-key branch. They are now handled as a dedicated special case before the whitelist lookup. (issue #85).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>

  <categories>
    <category>Audio</category>
    <category>Utility</category>
  </categories>

  <provides>
    <binary>asm-gui</binary>
  </provides>
</component>
