<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.github.loteran.arctis-sound-manager</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>

  <name>Arctis Sound Manager</name>
  <summary>Linux GUI for SteelSeries Arctis headsets</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      Arctis Sound Manager is a Linux application for configuring SteelSeries Arctis
      headsets. It provides a 4-channel audio mixer (Game / Chat / Media / HDMI),
      a full Sonar parametric EQ system, virtual 7.1 surround sound, and device management.
    </p>
    <p>Features:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>4-channel audio mixer with automatic media routing</li>
      <li>Sonar EQ — parametric EQ with 297+ presets, Spatial Audio, Smart Volume</li>
      <li>Micro processing — AI Noise Cancellation, Noise Gate, Compressor</li>
      <li>ANC / Transparent mode control from GUI and headset</li>
      <li>Virtual 7.1 surround via HeSuVi HRTF convolution</li>
      <li>10-band Custom EQ with save/load presets</li>
      <li>Device status — battery, mic mute, sidetone</li>
    </ul>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">ArctisManager.desktop</launchable>
  <icon type="remote" width="128" height="128">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/loteran/Arctis-Sound-Manager/main/docs/images/arctis-manager-icon.png</icon>

  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/loteran/Arctis-Sound-Manager</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/loteran/Arctis-Sound-Manager/issues</url>

  <developer id="com.github.loteran">
    <name>loteran</name>
  </developer>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>Home — 4-channel audio mixer</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/loteran/Arctis-Sound-Manager/main/docs/images/screenshot_home.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Sonar — Parametric EQ with presets</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/loteran/Arctis-Sound-Manager/main/docs/images/screenshot_sonar.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Equalizer — 10-band Custom EQ</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/loteran/Arctis-Sound-Manager/main/docs/images/screenshot_equalizer.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Headset / DAC — Device info</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/loteran/Arctis-Sound-Manager/main/docs/images/screenshot_headset.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />

  <releases>
    <release version="1.1.82" date="2026-06-24">
      <description>
        <p>Audio cuts in and out in Steam Game Mode / Gamescope (Bazzite, SteamOS) — under Gamescope, WirePlumber keeps reshuffling routing, so the loopback watchdog saw a permanent mislink and recreated the Arctis_Game / Arctis_Chat / Arctis_Media loopbacks every few seconds, each recreation causing a brief cut, looping forever. The watchdog now has an anti-flapping guard: when a channel is recreated 3 times within 30 s it enters a cooldown (60 s, doubling up to 5 min) during which it is left alone — a stable loopback, even if temporarily mislinked, is far less disruptive than constant cuts. (#90). Filter-chain crash-loop left audio permanently broken (Steam Deck / SteamOS) — when the PipeWire filter-chain SIGSEGVs on startup (e.g. a LADSPA plugin present in a Distrobox container but missing on the host), systemd restarted it endlessly, so the virtual sinks kept appearing and disappearing. ASM now detects the crash-loop, moves its EQ configs aside ("safe mode") and restarts once more to give flat-but-stable audio instead of perpetual cuts. (#88). Phantom "update available" that never goes away (Fedora and similar) — a leftover pip install --user copy in ~/.local shadowed the distro package on sys.path, so ASM read that stale copy's old version and nagged about an update that was already installed. ASM now reports the version of the package actually running, detects a shadowing pip install and shows a clear "multiple installations detected" message instead, and the dnf update command uses --refresh so a real new version is never hidden by stale COPR metadata.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.81" date="2026-06-20">
      <description>
        <p>YouTube and browser audio silent when ASM is running — sonar-output-eq was generated with media.class = Audio/Sink/Internal even in bypass mode, making it invisible to normal apps. WirePlumber had memorised Firefox → effect_input.sonar-output-eq in its stream-properties database, then refused to connect any new stream to that node (Internal nodes cannot be targeted by PulseAudio-compat clients), leaving Firefox suspended with no sink. The node is now Audio/Sink with priority.session = 1 so apps can connect to it while it is never auto-selected as the default output. Same fix applied to the active 8-channel path. Audio routing broken after daemon restart without the system tray — the arctis-manager systemd unit now declares Wants=filter-chain.service and After=filter-chain.service. Previously, restarting the daemon alone left the filter-chain stopped, causing all Sonar EQ loopbacks (sonar-game-eq, sonar-chat-eq, sonar-media-eq) to become orphaned and be recreated every 15 s until WirePlumber degraded. System tray forced Arctis_Game as default sink unconditionally on startup — the GUI start() method called pactl set-default-sink Arctis_Game regardless of headset state. When the headset was off, Firefox and any other app opening after ASM started were routed to a dead sink. Default-sink redirection is now owned exclusively by the daemon (redirect_audio_on_connect / on_disconnect logic).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.80" date="2026-06-20">
      <description>
        <p>3 new Sonar EQ presets from SteelSeries GG 113.0.0 — *007 First Light*, *Subnautica 2* and *Virtua Fighter 5 R.E.V.O World Stage* are now bundled for the Game channel. Output (HDMI) channel silent after profile switch or device change — the sonar-output-eq filter-chain config hardcoded audio.channels = 8 and a stale node.target pointing to a non-existent hdmi-surround71 device. ASM now queries PipeWire at config-write time to detect the active HDMI/DisplayPort sink and adapts channel count and position automatically (2.0 stereo, 5.1 surround, 7.1 surround). HDMI sinks are preferred over S/PDIF in auto-detection. Flat EQ for presets in SteelSeries GG 113+ format — GG 113.0.0 changed the preset export format, wrapping all settings under a data key. Affected bundled presets (*Forza Horizon 6*, *Deep Rock Galactic: Rogue Core*, *Lineage 2*) were silently rendered as flat/bypass. The parser now handles both formats.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.79" date="2026-06-19">
      <description>
        <p>pacman mirror 404 auto-retry in deps dialog — when installing a missing dependency via the system deps dialog on Arch/CachyOS, a desynchronized mirror (HTTP 404 on the package file) caused the install to fail silently. The dialog now captures pacman output, detects the mirror-sync error pattern, and automatically retries with pacman -Syy to force a database refresh before running the original install command. A guard flag prevents infinite retry loops.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.78" date="2026-06-19">
      <description>
        <p>3 new Sonar EQ presets from SteelSeries GG 113.0.0 — *Pure*, *Precision* and *Immersion* from the official SteelSeries GG 113.0.0 preset list are now bundled for the Game, Chat and Media channels. Per-channel EQ apply no longer interrupts the sibling channel — applying a preset or sliders on the Game channel used to restart both the Game and Media loopbacks (and vice-versa), causing a ~1.5 s audio cut on the channel that was not touched. The apply-worker now calls the new RecreateLoopbackSingle D-Bus method to restart only the loopback for the channel that was actually edited. Chat remains unaffected as before. (issue #85 — thanks @cookiekiller!). **weather_* settings no longer spam [ERROR] Unknown general setting configuration** — weather_enabled, weather_location, weather_lat, weather_lon, weather_units and weather_city_display are stored in GeneralSettings but had no matching ConfigSetting entry, so every SetSetting D-Bus call hit the unknown-key branch. They are now handled as a dedicated special case before the whitelist lookup. (issue #85).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.77" date="2026-06-18">
      <description>
        <p>Loopback watchdog recreated loopbacks every 5 s, breaking Discord routing — _loopback_watchdog treated a None link target (loopback not yet wired by WirePlumber) as a mislink and immediately recreated the loopback. This caused Discord's audio streams to lose their target sink every 5–10 seconds and repeatedly fall back to the system default, ignoring any routing_overrides entries. A grace period of 3 consecutive ticks (15 s) is now applied before acting on a None link: transient PipeWire graph states are ignored, while genuinely orphaned loopbacks (stuck unlinked for &gt; 15 s) are still recovered. (#84)</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.76" date="2026-06-17">
      <description>
        <p>Update banner persisted after upgrading via package manager — the "update available" banner on the Home page was never hidden when a re-check found no newer version: on_update_available returned early on an empty result without calling _update_banner.hide(). The banner would therefore remain visible for the rest of the session even after the user updated externally (apt/pacman/dnf). Now the banner is explicitly hidden when the check confirms the installed version is current. Additionally, the manual "Check for updates" button in the Settings page now also drives the Home page banner (via DevicePage.sig_update_result), so clicking "Check for updates" after an external upgrade instantly clears the stale notification without requiring a restart.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.75" date="2026-06-16">
      <description>
        <p>Arctis Nova Pro Omni — battery display showed values above 1000% — the Omni firmware reports headset and GameDAC battery as a direct 0–100 percentage value, but nova_pro_omni.yaml had perc_max: 8 (inherited from the Nova Pro Wireless which uses a 0–8 discrete scale). The formula raw × 100 ÷ 8 turned a 92% charge into 1150% and a 98% charge into 1225%. Setting perc_max: 100 for both headset_battery_charge and charge_slot_battery_charge corrects the display.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.74" date="2026-06-13">
      <description>
        <p>Headset name on Channels tab — the connected headset model name is now displayed above the status pills. If the headset is offline, the last known name is shown in gray. Ko-fi support button in sidebar — a compact Ko-fi button and "You like it ? Support me !" label appear at the bottom of the sidebar, below the ASM logo. ASM logo in sidebar — the logo is displayed above the support section and links to the GitHub repository when clicked.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.73" date="2026-06-13">
      <description>
        <p>USB autosuspend not disabled for already-connected dongles — udevadm trigger does not retroactively apply sysfs attributes to USB interfaces that are already active when the udev rule is installed or updated. Devices plugged in before the update kept autosuspend enabled, causing [Errno 19] No such device disconnects every 2–3 minutes and the GUI to never show the headset as Connected. After udevadm trigger, ASM now also writes on directly to /sys/bus/usb/devices/*/power/control for every connected SteelSeries device via sysfs, taking effect immediately without requiring a replug. (#80). Switching an app back to Output (HDMI) channel silenced audio — clicking G/C/M in the mixer called pw-metadata 0 default.configured.audio.sink to change the PipeWire global default sink. This caused the effect_input.sonar-output-eq filter-chain node to re-target its output to the newly chosen virtual sink instead of HDMI; switching back to O routed the stream into the EQ chain whose physical output had been silently redirected. The global default must never be changed for per-app routing — pulse.sink_input_move() alone is sufficient and is now the only call made. NameError: TEXT_SECONDARY crash after successful preset import via link — _set_status() in the import dialog used the bare constant TEXT_SECONDARY instead of _theme.c("TEXT_SECONDARY"), crashing the dialog after every successful link import at the status update step.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.72" date="2026-06-13">
      <description>
        <p>Line Out controls for Nova Pro Wireless and Nova Elite — the physical 3.5 mm LINE OUT jack on the GameDAC Gen 2 station is now configurable directly from the ASM DAC tab. A new Station Output section appears above the OLED options and is automatically hidden for headsets without a station DAC. The section contains:. Line Out Mode button group: *Speaker* (amplified output for passive speakers) or *Stream* (digital controlled output). Left / Right / Aux volume sliders (0–100 %) — visible only when mode is set to *Stream*, using a single multi-value HID command [0x47, left, right, aux] per adjustment.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.71" date="2026-06-13">
      <description>
        <p>Arctis Nova Pro Wireless X (PID 0x225d) — third hardware variant of the Nova Pro Wireless X, identified in the upstream elegos/Linux-Arctis-Manager project. Uses the same protocol as the existing 0x12e0/0x12e5 variants; all features (EQ, ANC, mic, surround) work identically.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.70" date="2026-06-13">
      <description>
        <p>Device shown as "No device detected" in GUI for always-connected headsets — devices without an online_status block (e.g. Arctis Nova 3 family) produced an empty D-Bus status dict even after the daemon had successfully initialised them, causing the GUI to display "No device detected" indefinitely. A sentinel headset_power_status: online is now injected when _device_ready is True and no status representation is defined. (#80). "Failed to find sink Arctis_Game" error at startup — redirect_audio was called immediately after spawning the pw-loopback processes, before PipeWire had registered the virtual sink. The method now retries up to 5 times (× 0.4 s) before giving up, eliminating the race condition on normal hardware. The final failure is now logged as WARNING instead of ERROR since the sink may legitimately be absent if loopback creation failed upstream. (#80).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.69" date="2026-06-13">
      <description>
        <p>Game and Media channels silent on NixOS module installs — two root causes addressed:. HeSuVi surround graph crashes when plate_1423 (swh-plugins) is absent — on distros without swh-plugins installed, the Distance reverb LADSPA node was generated unconditionally, causing filter-chain to exit immediately. The Distance effect is now silently disabled when plate_1423.so is not found in the standard LADSPA directories, giving working surround without the reverb rather than a crash-loop. (#79).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.68" date="2026-06-12">
      <description>
        <p>asm-setup crashed on NixOS with FileNotFoundError: update-desktop-database — NixOS and other immutable distros don't ship this tool. The call already used check=False but subprocess.Popen raises FileNotFoundError before the return-code check when the binary is absent. The call is now wrapped in try/except FileNotFoundError and silently skipped. (#79). HRIR file from Nix store (3.6 KB stub) passed validation and was never replaced — the Nix store copy has a valid RIFF header in its first 4 bytes but is far too short to be a usable 7.1 impulse response, causing Game and Media channels to be silent. _hrir_valid() now requires the file to exceed 10 KB in addition to having a RIFF header. asm-setup also tries the bundled hrir_assets/ profiles first (no network required) before downloading from GitHub. (#79).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.67" date="2026-06-12">
      <description>
        <p>Microphone monitor source selected instead of real mic — on some setups PipeWire exposes a monitor source before the real capture source, causing ASM to route apps to the monitor loopback instead of the physical microphone. The physical-source lookup now filters out device.class = monitor entries. (#80). Mic audio bypassed Sonar EQ — applications could connect directly to the ALSA source and skip the sonar-micro-eq filter chain. ASM now sets priority.session = 1010 on the Sonar virtual source and explicitly sets it as the default PulseAudio source at startup, so apps land on the EQ pipeline by default. D-Bus status returned {} when device was connected but status bytes unresolved — if the device was ready but device_status was None, the GUI showed "No device detected" even though the headset was online. The D-Bus GetStatus method now synthesises an online sentinel from online_status.online_value in that case.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.66" date="2026-06-12">
      <description>
        <p>HRIR selection silently failed on NixOS (and any read-only source) — apply_hrir_choice used shutil.copy2 which preserves source file permissions and mtime. Since HRIR WAVs live in the Nix store (read-only, epoch timestamp), the copied hrir.wav was also read-only; any subsequent profile selection in Settings → Spatial Audio would fail silently and the convolver would load an invalid file, leaving the Game and Media channels silent while Chat (which bypasses the convolver) still worked. Fixed by unlinking the destination before copying and using shutil.copy (no metadata). (#79). Uninstaller failed on Bazzite / immutable distros when run via curl | bash — the Distrobox delegation path resolved SCRIPT_DIR from BASH_SOURCE[0], which is stdin when piped through curl. The local scripts/distrobox/uninstall.sh was never found and the script exited with an error. Now fetches both _common.sh and distrobox/uninstall.sh to a temporary directory and delegates from there when the local path is unavailable. Added a dedicated NixOS installation section to the README covering both flake and classic (non-flake) paths, with a prominent warning that Settings → Spatial Audio must be opened on first launch to select an HRIR profile — without this step the Game and Media channels are silent.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.65" date="2026-06-10">
      <description>
        <p>OLED splash screen persisted over custom display on devices without a live PipeWire session — the refresh loop slept for the full 5 s REFRESH_INTERVAL even when the 3 s splash had already expired, leaving a ~2 s gap where the device firmware reclaimed the OLED and showed its native UI alongside ASM's splash content. The loop now wakes immediately at splash expiry so the first custom-display frame is pushed without delay. (#76). No interrupt OUT endpoint warning flooded the journal every 2 s — for devices without an interrupt OUT endpoint on their command interface (e.g. Arctis 1 Wireless), ASM correctly falls back to HID SET_REPORT but was logging a WARNING on every status poll. The warning is now emitted once per device attach; subsequent occurrences are downgraded to DEBUG. The flag is reset on teardown so the warning reappears on reconnect. (#74). recreate_loopbacks storm when filter-chain.service crashed repeatedly — if the SteelSeries Sonar filter-chain service crashed and restarted every few seconds (common in Distrobox), each pw-loopback exit triggered a D-Bus RecreateLoopbacks call, causing a rapid stop/start cycle with no net benefit. Calls are now debounced to at most once per 5 s; legitimate Sonar ↔ simple mode switches are unaffected. (#74).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.64" date="2026-06-10">
      <description>
        <p>Multi-theme support — ASM now ships 5 built-in colour themes (SteelSeries, Dark, Light, Ocean, Forest). The active theme is persisted in settings and can be switched live from the device page without restarting the application; every page, dialog and tray menu follows the change immediately. Enhanced bug report diagnostics — PipeWire / container runtime — the automatic bug report now collects the data needed to diagnose audio-routing failures in Distrobox and other container environments: $PIPEWIRE_RUNTIME_DIR, $PULSE_SERVER, container type (Distrobox / Flatpak / Snap / Docker / native), status of pipewire, pipewire-pulse, wireplumber and filter-chain user services, Arctis-filtered PipeWire nodes from pw-dump (with pactl fallback), PipeWire sources, and the last journal entries for pipewire and filter-chain. A missing or empty Arctis-nodes section in a report is now a direct indicator that PipeWire cannot see the device — eliminating the back-and-forth follow-up that issue #74 required.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.63" date="2026-06-09">
      <description>
        <p>Arctis Nova Pro Wired — OLED screen never updated and the daemon spammed OLED USB error: [Errno 110] Operation timed out — the GameDAC Gen 2 firmware validates the HID SET_REPORT wValue strictly, but ASM sent report id 0 in its low byte, so the base station rejected every OLED transfer. The wValue is now built as (report_type &lt;&lt; 8) | report_id (0x0306 for image frames, 0x0206 for brightness/return-to-UI), matching the protocol proven by working third-party tools. (#76). Arctis Nova Pro Wired — headset not detected after boot/login until audio activity (e.g. joining a call) woke the device — a device already plugged in at startup fires no udev add event, so a single failed initial scan was never retried. The daemon now re-scans periodically until the device is fully configured instead of waiting for a hotplug or USB wake event. (#76). Arctis Nova Pro Wired — audio near-inaudible unless volume was cranked to ~95% — control-transfer device commands carried the same incorrect wValue, so the high-gain initialisation never reached the GameDAC. Commands now embed the correct report id in the wValue for devices that require it, opt-in per device so the Nova 7 family and others are unaffected. (#76).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.62" date="2026-06-09">
      <description>
        <p>Font rendering on Bazzite/Linux — all text displayed as blocks — Qt's QSS parser does not support the CSS Level 4 system-ui keyword; it treated it as a literal font name, found nothing, and fell back to a font rendering all glyphs as tofu squares. Replaced with sans-serif, which Qt resolves correctly via fontconfig on all Linux distributions.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.61" date="2026-06-08">
      <description>
        <p>Automatic Sonar preset sync — ASM now downloads new SteelSeries Sonar presets automatically at startup (once per 24 h). A  lists all official presets; the new  fetches it, detects missing presets, and downloads them silently in background to . 3 new Sonar game presets: Forza Horizon 6, Lineage 2, Deep Rock Galactic: Rogue Core. GitHub Action —  auto-regenerates  whenever preset files are pushed to  or .</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.60" date="2026-06-08">
      <description>
        <p>Fedora COPR install failed with a python3-dbus-next file conflict — the RPM bundled the dbus_next module, which collides with Fedora's own python3-dbus-next package (shipped since F40). ASM now bundles dbus-next only on distros whose repos don't provide it, and depends on the system package otherwise: Fedora ≥ 40 use python3-dbus-next, older Fedora still bundle, and the Debian/Ubuntu build auto-detects availability per series. (#73)</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.59" date="2026-06-07">
      <description>
        <p>Arctis Nova Pro Omni: gain and mic sidetone now work — re-analysing the USB capture by opcode showed the Omni uses opcode 0x18 for sidetone (not 0x39, which it ignores) and shifted gain values (low=0x00/high=0x01 instead of 0x01/0x02). The device profile is corrected accordingly. (#70). Arctis Nova Pro Omni: OLED screen support — the OLED driver is now parameterised per device (HID interface, report id, SET_REPORT wValue, dimensions) instead of being hard-coded for the Nova Pro Wireless. The Omni's screen is driven on interface 3 with report id 0x01 / wValue 0x0200, which also stops the OLED Resource busy errors it was logging. The Nova Pro Wireless path is unchanged.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.58" date="2026-06-06">
      <description>
        <p>Arctis Nova Pro Omni controls had no effect — a real Windows USB capture of SteelSeries GG driving the Omni (firmware 1.32.0) revealed its HID control commands lead with report id 0x01, not 0x06 (Nova Pro Wireless) nor 0x07 (previously inferred from third-party OLED drivers). The device profile now leads every command with 0x01 and polls status with 0x01b0; the per-setting opcodes are byte-for-byte identical to the Nova Pro Wireless. Gain, mic, sidetone, EQ, ANC and the other controls should now take effect on the Omni. (#70)</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.57" date="2026-06-06">
      <description>
        <p>OLED weather (and all custom-display content) could vanish after the DAC re-enumerated — the Arctis Nova Pro Wireless re-enumerates on the USB bus at boot, wake and replug. The daemon overwrote its libusb handle without releasing the previous one, so the stale handle kept the interface claimed and every later transfer failed with EBUSY (Resource busy), blanking the custom OLED display and blocking device commands. The handle is now fully released (dispose_resources) before re-claiming on same-device re-enumeration. "Show city" weather toggle on the DAC tab could not be turned off — oled_show_weather_city had no matching configuration entry, so the D-Bus SetSetting call was rejected and the toggle snapped back to on. Added the missing entry. Vertical OLED scroll no longer triggers when the content essentially fits — the layout height was over-counted (separator double-count plus excess weather padding); the natural height now mirrors the real render and a small scroll deadzone was added, so a near-full screen stays still instead of jittering.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.56" date="2026-06-06">
      <description>
        <p>Arctis Nova Pro Omni controls — the Omni (0x2290) now has its own device profile targeting the correct USB layout: control interface 3 (the 64-byte HID endpoint) with HID SET_REPORT transport. In 1.1.55 it reused the Nova Pro Wireless profile (interface 4 with an interrupt-OUT endpoint the Omni does not expose), so the UI appeared but the controls had no effect. DAC command opcodes are still assumed identical to the Nova Pro Wireless, pending confirmation.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.55" date="2026-06-06">
      <description>
        <p>Arctis Nova Pro Omni support — added product ID 0x2290 to the Arctis Nova Pro Wireless device profile. Audio routing (Game/Chat/Media mixer, HeSuVi spatial surround, Sonar EQ) and HID controls are enabled by reusing the Nova Pro Wireless DAC protocol. The status protocol is assumed identical and not yet confirmed by a USB capture, so some reported status values may be inaccurate until verified.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.54" date="2026-06-03">
      <description>
        <p>Arctis GameBuds / GameBuds X support — initial device support for the Arctis GameBuds (PS5/PC, 0x230a) and GameBuds X for Xbox (0x2317) via their 2.4 GHz USB dongle. Supported controls: mic volume, sidetone (Off/Low/Medium/High), noise cancelling mode (Off/Transparency/ANC), ANC/transparency level, volume limiter, wear sense, and auto power-off (up to 90 min). Protocol reverse-engineered from a USB capture; battery level and connection status are not yet available (status protocol unknown).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.53" date="2026-06-02">
      <description>
        <p>Left-click the tray icon to open the window — a single left-click on the Arctis Sound Manager system-tray icon now opens the main window (launching it the first time, raising and focusing it afterwards). Previously the window could only be reached through the tray's right-click context menu. Right-click still shows the context menu.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>

  <categories>
    <category>Audio</category>
    <category>Utility</category>
  </categories>

  <provides>
    <binary>asm-gui</binary>
  </provides>
</component>
